Vowel and consonant overview. Real words. Apply the phonetic sound to the entire
column, no matter what the spelling is. Then read each row across, making the
vowel distinctions.
saw, shawl, tall, thought, vaughn, walk, yawn, czar, bat, chat, dad, fat, gap, had,
Jack. Cat. Laugh. Mad. Nan. Pat. Ran. Sat. Shack. Tack. That. Vat. Wax. Yap. Zap.
Bet. Check. Dead. Fetch. Get. Head. Jeff. Ken. Left. Men. Net. Pet. Read. Said.
Shed. Ten. Then. Vex. When. Yes. Zen. Ben, chin, did, fit, give, his, gin, kid, lick,
mix, knit, pick, rib, sin, shill, tin, This. Vim. With. Yip. Zig. Book. Foot.
Good. Hood. Could. Look. Nook. Put. Rook. Soot. Should. Took. Wood. Yule. Butt.
Chuck. Done. Fun. Gun. hut, jump, come, luck, much, none, putt, rub, such, shut,
tub, the, vogue, was, young, ZUG, BEAT, CHEAT, DEAL, FEET, GEESE, HEA, JEANS, KEY,
LEAD, ME, NEED, PEAK, REED, SEE, SHEA, tea, these, feel, we, yield, zeal, boat,
choke, don't, phone, go, hold, joke, cold, load, most, note, pull, row, sew, show,
tow, though, voice, won't, yo-yo, Zoe, boot, choose, do, food, ghoul, who, jewel,
cool, lose, moon, new, pool, room, suit, shoe, tube, through, voodoo, woo, you zoo
bait chase day fail gate hey jail cane lay make name pay raise say Shape. Take. They.
Veil. Whales. Yale. Zany. Bite. Child. Die. Find. Guy. High. Giant. Kite. Lie.
Mine. Knife. Pie. Rise. Sigh. Shine. Try. Thigh. Vi. Why. Yikes. Zygote. Ought, at,
etch, it, um, eat, oat, oops, ate, I'm, bob, bat, bet, bin, book, but, beat, boat,
boot, bait, bite CHOP, CHAT, CHECK, CHIN, CHUCK, CHEAT, CHOKE, CHOOSE, CHASE, CHILD
DAWN, DAD, DEAD, DID, DONE, DEAL, DON'T, DO, DAY, DIE Fawn, fat, fetch, fit, foot,
fun, feet, phone, food, fail, find, gone, gap, get, give, good, gun, geese, go,
ghoul, gate, guy, hot, had, head, his, hood, hut, he, hold, who, hey, Hi. Jaw.
Jack. Jeff. Gin. Jump. Jeans. Joke. Jewel. Jail. Giant. Call. Cat. Ken. Kid. Could.
Come. Key. Cold. Cool. Cane. Kite. Law, laugh, left, lick, look, luck, lead, load,
lose, lay, lie. Mom, mad, men, mix, much, me, most, moon, make, mine. Not, nan, net,
nit, nook, none, need, note, new, name, knife. Pot, pat, pet, pick, put, put,
peak, pole, pool, pay, pie. Raw, ran, read, rib, rook, rub, read, row, room,
raise, rise. Saw, sat, said, sin, soot, such, see, sow, suit, say, sigh. Shawl,
shack, shed, shill, should, shut, see, show, shoe, shape, shine. Tall, tack, ten,
tin, took, tub, tee, toe, tube, take, try. thought, that, then, this, the, these,
though, through, they, thigh, von, that, vex, vim, vug, veal, voice, voodoo, veil,
vie, Walk. Wax. When. With. Would. Was. We. Won't. Woo. Whales. Why. Yawn. Yap.
Yes. Yip. Yull. Young. Yield. Yo-yo. You. Yale. Yikes. ZAR, ZAP, ZEN, ZIG, ZUG,
ZEAL, ZOE, ZOO, ZANY, ZYGOAT.